pcworld.in 2011-12-06

# Privacy Policy | PC World India

**1.   IDG Media Private Ltd. ONLINE PRIVACY POLICY**

The PCWorld Web site and associated sites are maintained by

IDG Media Private Ltd. (“IDG India”)  
No. 49, 3rd. Cross, Mission Road  
Bangalore 560 027  
India

PCWorld.in collects personally identifying information and data about individuals, their company, and the companies demographics (“personally identifying information and data”) including:    
(i) when you provide information to PCWorld.in, such as when you register or sign up for any of our products such as publications, subscriptions, e-mails, contests, newsletters, memberships, RSS Feeds, content delivery via sms text or other technologies, webcasts, White Papers, online seminars, conferences and other communications with PCWorld.in,   
(ii) when you register or sign up on the PCWorld site or when you register for any other IDG Publishing Network products individually or through “auto register”, your information will be known to PCWorld.  
(iii) from time to time we may add other information that  we collect from third party sources to enhance the information that you provided to PCWorld.in  
Below is the current policy regarding the usage of personally identifying information and data collected by PCWorld.in. We reevaluate this policy on an ongoing basis based on feedback from readers.   PCWorld.in reserves the right to change its privacy policy. However, if there are any changes to the use of personally identifiying information and data that is different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you by posting a notice on our website.   

PCWorld.in or one of our IDG affiliated companies, or third party partners may place a "cookie" in the browser files of a user's computer. The cookie itself does not contain any personally identifying information, except when such information has been supplied by a subscriber or registered user.

If you have registered with PCWorld.in, the information in your "cookie" is used to provide a more personalized experience on our Web site.

For example, in our forums, a cookie allows us to show you which posted messages are new since your last log-in.

If you haven't registered with our site, we may place a cookie on your system to help provide a more personalized experience on PCWorld.in. This cookie identifies you as a unique user by means of a tracking ID. However, if you have not registered on our site, we cannot link that user ID with personal identifying information and data about you such as your name or e-mail address.

Other cookies without personally identifying information and data are used to enable PCWorld.in to manage the banner advertisements presented or personalized information to the user.

Browsers or third-party software can allow you to block the use of cookies while you surf our site. Or, you can use third-party "anonymizer" services to mask information in your cookies, or even general data such as your IP address. In such cases you would not be able to take advantage of most of the personalization services offered by PCWorld.in

The aggregated information we collect is used for a number of purposes including the following :  
1.    to improve the content and design of the PCWorld Web site   
2.    to enable our audit bureau to verify our claims of traffic to the site   
3.    to help advertisers, potential advertisers or marketers assess the suitability of the site for their ad campaigns   
4.    as clear GIFs, also known as pixel tags, provided by our ad-serving company to help manage online advertising. These clear GIFS let our ad-serving company recognize a browser's cookie when a user visits our site. The information we collect and share through this technology is not personally identifiable (It does not include your name, address, telephone number or e-mail address). For more information about our ad-serving company or for your choices about not having this anonymous information used, please visit [www.doubleclick.net](http://www.doubleclick.net/ "www.doubleclick.net")   
5.    PCWorld has contracted with DoubleClick. to serve all advertising on [www.pcworld.in](http://www.pcworld.in/ "www.pcworld.in"), both on the Web site itself and through its e-mail newsletters. When DoubleClick is serving ads, it recognizes certain types of non-personally identifiable information, such as a user's IP address, browser version or type, operating system, service provider and time zone. DoubleClick also uses cookies to note the general content of the sites that users visit over time in order to serve ads on this site and other sites. Any pages a user calls up on [www.pcworld.in](http://www.pcworld.in/ "www.pcworld.in") aren't connected with personally identifiable information collected either at [www.pcworld.in](http://www.pcworld.in/ "www.pcworld.in") or elsewhere. For more details about the non-personally identifiable information DoubleClick collects and the opportunity to opt out of such data collection, please visit [www.doubleclick.net/privacy_policy/](http://www.doubleclick.net/privacy_policy/ "www.doubleclick.net/privacy_policy/"). We use web metric vendors to gather information to help us understand how users utilize our websites and other electronic products.  
6.    We may create and use aggregate customer data to understand more about the interests of our customers and may use the data to offer goods and services we believe may be of interest to our customers, on behalf of PCWorld, its sister IDG companies, or select organizations.   
Postal addresses, and other personally identifying information and data will be used to promote PCWorld and other IDG companies ‘ products and services, and may be rented and/or licensed to selected outside firms for promotional purposes. Offers for which the personally identifying information and data are rented and/or licensed for use and the users are required to target their offers carefully.

Telephone numbers of PCWorld print subscribers are used by PCWorld to collect re-qualification data and may be used by PCWorld, IDG and other IDG companies, affiliates and it's advertisers for promotional purposes. PCWorld may rent and/or license for use phone numbers to selected outside firms for promotional purposes. Offers for which the numbers are rented and/or licensed for use are required to target their offers carefully.

Mobile telephone numbers that are provided to PCWorld will be used to provide the products and services you’ve specifically requested, such as, but not limited to content delivery via sms text or other technologies, and for customer service related to the products and services you’ve requested.  With your express consent, your mobile telephone number may be used to promote other products and services of PCWorld, as well as the products and services of other IDG companies.  Further, your mobile phone number may, with your express consent, be used to promote the products and services of carefully chosen third parties.  At any time you may “opt-out” of receiving communications via your mobile phone from PCWorld, other IDG companies, and third parties, by clicking the unsubscribe link of any individual message you may receive. Because many phone companies recycle phone numbers, it is possible for users who purchase a new phone to receive messages that the previous owner had subscribed to or otherwise consented to receive.   
Fax numbers of PCWorld print subscribers are used by PCWorld to collect re-qualification data and may be used for surveys for PCWorld and third parties. Except as set forth in this policy no fax numbers are rented and/or licensed to outside firms.

E-mail addresses of PCWorld print subscribers are used for re-qualification purposes. These e-mail addresses may also be used to collect feedback by members of our editorial or research team, to promote PCWorld and IDG products and services, and they may be rented to other firms and/or licensed for promotional purposes.  When you provide your email address to us, you agree to receive email from PCWorld and its sister IDG companies, and the IDG Network. We allow users to "opt-out" of receiving e-mail from outside firms, however, when e-mail information is collected and with each e-mail use of the user's address you can individually “opt-out” of receiving further e-mail from outside firms, PCWorld, its sister IDG companies and the IDG Network If a user does not choose to “opt-out” at the time the e-mail address is collected, or does not respond to the questions concerning how we may use their email address, the address may be rented and/or licensed for use to outside firms. Offers for which the e-mail address is rented and/or licensed for use require the users to target their offers carefully.  

Users who later decide they want to change their preferences may do so at [www.pcworld.in](http://www.pcworld.in/ "www.pcworld.in")  
Personal identifying information submitted on portions of our site developed with outside third parties may be shared with those third parties, and the information will be governed by those parties' privacy policies as well as PCWorld's. PCWorld, nor any of its parent companies or any of its subsidiaries or affiliates do not bear any responsibility for any actions or policies of such third parties.

**Data processing in India and transfer to group members abroad**  
Your personally identifying information and data is stored on IDG India computers in India and may, for the purposes described above, be shared with other members of our Group. IDG India and/or other members of our Group may transfer your Personal Data to third party specialists for processing within India or outside of India, including the European Union or the United States.    
We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your personally identifying information and data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Use of data for Direct Marketing Purposes**  
Because IDG India is part of the IDG Publishing Network, IDG  India may use the information provided by you to send you offers that IDG India believes will be of interest to you from any of the IDG Publishing Network sites. You can always recall your consent concerning receiving additional information from the IDG Publishing Network and our Group. You also have the absolute right to ask us not to process your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes. While we give details in this Privacy Policy in relation to opting out, we want to make clear that you can at any time exercise this right by contacting us in the manner described above.   
****

**Third Party Data Processors**  
As stated above, your personally identifying information and data may be transferred to and stored by third party specialists engaged by IDG India and/or other members of our Group, to process your personally identifying information and data on our behalf (i.e. as data processors) and assist in the provision of the content and services you request. In all cases, IDG India will ensure that appropriate measures are taken to protect your personally identifying information and data. These third party providers will be obligated by IDG India to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally identifying information and data and to take adequate technical and organizational measures to protect your personally identifying information and data against loss and against any form of unlawful processing.    
In addition, if you consent to receive offerings from third party organizations, this personally identifying information and data remains with IDG India who will send the third party offerings.  Except as set forth below with regard to the provision of free resources, at no time will your Personal Data be transferred to such third party organizations.    
In order to provide you with free resources such as white papers and expert analysis, we may share your Personal Data and/or business information with third party organizations we partner with.  These third party organizations may be located within India or outside of India.      
PCWorld.in users should be aware that when they disclose personal identifying information (e.g., user name, address, company name, telephone number, demographic information, buying information, other data and E-mail address) in discussion forums, chat rooms or other areas that are publicly accessible by others, that information can be collected and used by others and may result in unsolicited messages from other posters or parties. PCWorld nor its parent company or any of its subsidiaries or affiliates are not responsible for any information that you provide in the above areas.   
In the event that part or all of the ownership of PCWorld or any of its products are sold or transferred, all lists and data which contains personally identifying information and data including  for  example user name, address, company  name, telephone number, demographic information, buying information, other data and e-mail address, will be transferred to the new owner.  
Also IDG India may disclose your personal data if IDG India is under a duty to disclose your Personal Data as a result of a court order or any other legal obligation, any subpoena or legal process or as otherwise required by law, or if we believe it necessary to prevent or take action regarding illegal activities or violations of our policies.

**2\. IDG PUBLISHING NETWORK ONLINE REGISTRATION PRIVACY POLICY**

Below is the current policy regarding the usage of personally identifying information and data collected by the IDG Publishing Network. We reevaluate this policy on an ongoing basis based on feedback from readers.  The IDG Publishing Network reserves the right to change its privacy policy.  However, if there are any changes to the use of personally identifiable information and data that is different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you by posting a notice on our website.   
****

**About the IDG Publishing Network**  
The International Data Group, Inc. (IDG) family of on-line and print publications consists of hundreds of award-winning titles including  PCWorld, CSO, Computerworld, Game Pro, Network World, Macworld and PC World. The IDG Publishing Network is a growing collection of IDG web sites that presently includes  cio.com, csoonline.com, infoworld.com, networkworld.com, macworld.com, pcworld.com and gamepro.com. A complete listing is available at [www.idg.com](http://www.idg.com/ "www.idg.com").

To access restricted content on any IDG Publishing Network web site you must be a member of the IDG Publishing Network. To become a member of the IDG Publishing Network, you need to provide certain information about yourself. Any of the IDG Publishing Network sites may use this identifying information for internal analytical and business development purposes and, to send you email. However, other forms of communication, including postal mail, may be directed to you pursuant to the site's specific privacy policy, as may be updated from time to time. 

You can "opt-out" of receiving further email by clicking the appropriate links that appear at the bottom of any email you receive. If you do not want to receive other types of communication, including as applicable, postal mail, from the editor and publisher of the site, please refer to the site's privacy policy for the procedure to follow. 

The IDG Publishing Network is intended for individuals over the age of 13 years old. Personal information may not be provided by anyone under 13 years of age. Further no one under 13 years old may participate in the forums or chat rooms or any other areas where public discussions may take place. In addition no one under that age of 18 may conduct any transactions for the purposes or purchasing or selling any items. Parents should be sure that their children are not conducting any of the above activities on the IDG Publishing Network.

If you have any questions or comments regarding the IDG Publishing Network or its use of information please send email to: [postmasterhelp@idgcommunications.com](mailto:postmasterhelp@idgcommunications.com)   
or write to us at IDG Publishing Network, C/O Customer Service, TSG, IDG Communications, Inc., 5 Speen St., Framingham, MA 01701. U.S.A.

Last updated: 30 March 2010.
